Guide to the Anaconda Copper Mining Company records 1876-1974
Montana Historical Society
- Diamond Coal and Coke Company (Diamondville, Wyoming)
  - Legal Documents
    - Agreement: stockholders and Marcus Daly, 1898 (Box-folder 405 / 6)
    - Agreements: The California Company, 1934-1938 (Box-folder 405 / 7)
    - Agreements: Oregon Short Line Railroad Company, 1897, 1920-1932 (Box-folder 405 / 8)
    - Agreement: Union Pacific Railroad Company, 1898 (Box-folder 405 / 9)
    - Agreements (re gravel), 1934-1937 (Box-folder 405 / 10)
    - Contract: Simon Sterne (includes royalty reports), 1900-1923 (Box-folder 405 / 11)
    - Deeds, 1906, 1912-1928, 1933-1942 (Box-folder 405 / 12-13)
    - Deeds and related papers (re property acquisition from Hams Fork coal Mining Company, et al.), 1894-1902 (Box-folder 405 / 14)
    - Leases (re grazing), 1908-1934 (Box-folder 405 / 15)
    - Leases, 1893-1911 (Box-folder 405 / 16)
    - "Mountain Trading Company" [company store], 1901 (Box-folder 405 / 17)
    - "Papers re land filings", 1897-1899 (Box-folder 405 / 18)
    - Rent agreements: miners' houses and tents, 1899 (Box-folder 405 / 19)
    - Union Pacific Railroad land transfer, 1899 (Box-folder 405 / 20)
    - Miscellaneous (includes telephone pole leases, billboard advertising permit and lease, and lease of Mountain Trading Company building for wool warehouse), 1936-1939 (Box-folder 405 / 21)
  - Organizational Records
    - Articles of incorporation, 1894 (Box-folder 406 / 1)
    - "Papers re shares held by Utah Commercial and Savings Bank", 1897-1898 (Box-folder 406 / 2)
    - Proxies; resignations; etc., 1898 (Box-folder 406 / 3)
    - Stockholder list, 1898 (Box-folder 406 / 4)
  - Reports
    - Report to U.S. Geological Survey (re coal production), 1905 (Box-folder 406 / 5)
    - William H. Schmidt report (re audit), 1900 (Box-folder 406 / 6)
    - F.W. Whyte report (re Diamondville coal), 1897 (Box-folder 406 / 7)
- Douglas Mining Company / Douglas-Pine Creek Company (Beeler and Masonia, Idaho)
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1917 (Box-folder 406 / 8)
  - Financial and Production Records
    - Insurance policies, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 406 / 9)
    - Labor distributions, etc., 1916-1918 (Box-folder 406 / 10)
    - Supplies on hand (includes Neihart Development Company, 1916), 1916-1918 (Box-folder 406 / 11)
    - Tunnel assays and tunnel work (includes Neihart Development Company, 1916), circa 1916-1918 (Box-folder 406 / 12)
  - Legal Documents
    - Agreement: Oregon-Washington Railroad and Navigation Company and Hypotheek Mining and Milling Company (re right-of-way at Douglas Mine), 1917 (Box-folder 406 / 13)
    - Explosives license, 1917 (Box-folder 406 / 14)
- Electric Railway, Light, and Power Company / Electric Light and Railway Department
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1895-1896 (Box-folder 406 / 15)
  - Financial Records
    - Balance sheets, 1898-1901 (Box-folder 406 / 16)
    - Business statements, 1890-1952 (Volume 639- 643)
    - Collections, 1889-1891 (Box-folder 406 / 17)
    - Construction costs, 1900-1901 (Box-folder 406 / 18)
    - General office ledgers, 1895-1900 (Volume 644- 645)
    - General office ledger index, 1898-1900 (Box-folder 406 / 19)
    - Inventory, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 406 / 20)
    - Journal entries (items prepared for entry in journal), 1904 (Box-folder 406 / 21)
    - Notice to conductors on fares, 1901 (Box-folder 406 / 22)
    - Record of goods received, 1901-1911 (Volume 646- 647)
    - Supply ledger, 1900-1904 (Volume 648)
    - Time book (re payroll), 1892-1896 (Box-folder 406 / 23)
    - Transcript of books, 1897, 1911-1916 (Box-folder 407 / 1-7)
    - Transcript of books, 1917-1922 (Box-folder 408 / 1-6)
    - Trial balances, 1898 (Box-folder 408 / 7)
    - Trial balances [Archives Map Case], 1898 (Oversize-folder 9)
    - U.S. corporate income tax, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 408 / 8)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contracts, 1894-1895 (Box-folder 408 / 9)
    - Ordinance for street railway (rough draft), 1888-1889 (Box-folder 408 / 10)
  - Miscellany
    - Injury reports, 1897-1915 (Box-folder 408 / 11-12)
    - Oversize Material [Archives Map Case], undated (Oversize-folder 9)
    - Injury reports, 1916-1935 (Box-folder 409 / 1-3)
- Elliston Fluming Company
  - Financial Records
    - Trial balances, 1889-1891 (Box-folder 409 / 4)
- Elm Orlu Mining Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Anaconda Copper Mining Company (re development work), 1925-1926 (Box-folder 409 / 4a)
  - Financial and Production Records
    - Accounts payable, 1909 (Box-folder 409 / 5)
    - Accounts receivable, 1927-1928 (Volume 649)
    - Audited vouchers (see voucher registers for earlier dates), 1914-1928 (Volume 650- 656)
    - Cash books, 1909-1928 (Volume 657- 664)
    - "Comparative weights and assays, etc.", 1914-1919 (Volume 665)
    - Copper-iron concentrates shipments and returns, 1914-1920 (Volume 666)
    - Copper ore shipments and returns, 1907-1927 (Volume 667- 668)
    - Elm Orlu Mine accounts, 1920-1928 (Volume 669)
    - Freight received, 1906-1910 (Volume 670)
    - Journals, 1906-1928 (Volume 671- 678)
    - Ledgers, 1906-1928 (Volume 679- 683)
    - Ore shipments, 1909-1927 (Volume 684- 687)
    - Silver and copper shipments, 1908-1909 (Volume 688)
    - Statements of flotation royalty, 1916-1922 (Box-folder 409 / 6)
    - Travona Mine: cash book, 1919-1921 (Volume 689)
    - Travona Mine: journal, 1919-1921 (Volume 690)
    - Travona Mine: ledger, 1919-1921 (Volume 691)
    - Travona Mine: voucher record, 1919-1921 (Volume 692)
    - Trial balance, April, November 1904 (Box-folder 409 / 7)
    - Voucher register (see audited vouchers for later dates), 1906-1913 (Volume 693- 694)
    - Zinc concentrate shipments and returns, 1909-1927 (Volume 695- 699)
    - "Zinc residue", 1909-1911 (Volume 700)
  - Legal Documents
    - Players' agreements for Clark Ball Club, 1923 (Box-folder 409 / 8)
  - Organizational Records
    - Annual statement, 1918 (Box-folder 409 / 9)
- Employees Club
  - Financial Records
    - Journal, 1953-1963 (Volume 701)
    - Ledger, 1947-1958 (Volume 702)
- Fertilizer Department (Chicago, Illinois; Conda, Idaho; Anaconda, Mont.)
  - Financial Records
    - Business statements, 1920-1933 (Volume 703)
    - Inventory, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 409 / 10)
    - Journal, 1929-1932 (Volume 704)
    - Transcript of books, 1920-1922 (Box-folder 409 / 11-13)
- Florence Hotel (Butte)
  - Financial Records
    - Account ledger, 1919-1920 (Volume 705)
    - Cash book, 1919-1920 (Volume 706)
    - Ledger, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 409 / 14)
    - Room rent book, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 410 / 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 410 / 2)
  - Miscellany
    - Hotel register, 1915-1917 (Volume 707)
    - Hotel register, 1917-1920 (Box-folder 410 / 3-4)
- Hope Lumber Manufacturing Company / Lumber Department (Hope, Idaho)
  - Financial Records
    - Audit, 1913 (Box-folder 410 / 5)
    - Business statements, 1908-1929 (Volume 708- 709)
    - Transcript of books, 1908-1914 (Box-folder 410 / 6-9)
    - Transcript of books, 1915-1922 (Box-folder 411 / 1-4)
    - Transcript of books, 1922-1925 (Volume 710)
    - U.S. corporate income tax, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 411 / 5)
- Interstate Lumber Company
  - Financial Records
    - Business statements, 1911-1941 (Volume 711)
    - Inventories: Anaconda yard, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 411 / 6)
    - Inventories: Butte yard, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 411 / 7)
    - Inventories: Deer Lodge yard, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 412 / 1)
    - Inventories: Hamilton yard, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 412 / 2)
    - Inventories: Helena yard, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 412 / 3)
    - Inventories: Missoula yard, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 412 / 4)
    - Inventories: Stevensville yard, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 412 / 5)
    - Inventories: Twin Bridges yard, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 412 / 6)
    - Inventories: Whitehall yard, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 412 / 7)
    - Transcript of books, 1911-1912 (Box-folder 412 / 8)
    - Transcript of books, 1913-1919 (Box-folder 413 / 1-7)
    - Transcript of books, 1920-1922 (Box-folder 414 / 1-3)
    - Transcript of books, 1922-1928 (Volume 712)
    - U.S. corporate income tax, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 414 / 4)
- J.T. Carroll Lumber Company
  - Financial Records
    - Audit, 1910 (Box-folder 414 / 5)
    - Balance sheets, profit and loss, 1914-1924 (Volume 713)
    - Inventories of fir lumber for flume at Anaconda, 1892 (Box-folder 414 / 6)
- Mayflower Mining Company
  - Financial Records
    - Journal, 1896-1927 (Box-folder 414 / 7)
    - Ledger, 1896-1959 (Box-folder 414 / 8-9)
- Mill Creek Timber Company
  - Financial Records
    - Balance sheets, profit and loss (includes Mill Creek Irrigation Company and Mines Timber Company), 1914-1938 (Volume 714)
    - Cash book, 1923-1927 (Volume 715)
    - General ledger, 1923-1927 (Volume 716)
    - Journal, 1919-1931 (Volume 717)
    - Transcript of books, 1913-1922 (Box-folder 415 / 1-3)
    - U.S. corporate income tax, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 415 / 4)
- Mines Office
  - Financial and Production Records
    - Average rate of compensation (re wages), 1928-1944 (Volume 718)
    - Cash book (primarily royalty payments), 1896-1897 (Box-folder 415 / 5)
    - Cost sheets (six-month reports), 1905-1957 (Volume 719- 741)
    - Cost sheets (yearly report), 1964 (Volume 742)
    - Disbursement sheets, 1895-1900 (Volume 743- 744)
    - Inventory, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 415 / 6-7)
    - Inventory: Leonard Mine, 1935 (Box-folder 415 / 8)
    - Ledgers, 1895-1898, 1917-1926 (Volume 745- 747)
    - Machine Shop order book, 1896 (Volume 748)
    - Mine tonnages: copper, zinc, manganese, 1926-1951 (Volume 749)
    - "Move orders" (re transfer of equipment, etc., between mines), 1915-1921 (Box-folder 415 / 9)
    - Ore shipments (daily), 1904 (Volume 750- 751)
    - Payroll journal (lists payroll total for each mine, September 1917-March 1918), 1917-1925 (Volume 752)
    - Payroll journal, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 416 / 1)
    - Stope cost record [Archives Map Case], 1920 (Oversize-folder 14)
    - Unemployment compensation eligibility, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 416 / 2)
    - Voucher record, 1900-1902 (Volume 753)
  - Minutes
    - Notes of foremen's meetings (re Zinc Group of Mines and efficiency), 1917-1919 (Box-folder 416 / 2a)
- Mines Timber Company
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1924-1927 (Box-folder 416 / 3)
    - Journal, 1917-1931 (Volume 754)
    - Ledger, 1918-1927 (Volume 755)
    - Transcript of books, 1911-1922 (Box-folder 416 / 4-7)
    - U.S. corporate income tax, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 416 / 8)
- Montana Copper Company
  - Organizational Records
    - Articles of incorporation, 1879 (Box-folder 417 / 1)
- Montana Free Press
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 417 / 2)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1928-1930 (Volume 756)
    - Voucher register, 1928-1930 (Volume 757)
  - Organizational Records
    - Bylaws, 1928 (Box-folder 417 / 3)
    - Minute book (includes articles of incorporation), 1928-1933 (Volume 758)
- Montana Hardware Company
  - Financial Records
    - Balance sheets, profit and loss, 1928-1949 (Volume 759)
- Montana Hotel / Hotel Department (Anaconda)
  - Financial Records
    - Balance sheets, profit and loss, 1896-1904 (Box-folder 417 / 4)
    - Business statements (Vol. 762 includes Western Hotel Company, operated under lease, 1933-1940), 1901-1949 (Volume 760- 762)
    - Cost of remodelling, 1903 (Box-folder 417 / 5)
    - Inventory, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 417 / 6)
    - Inventory, 1947 (Volume 763)
    - Ledgers, 1895-1905 (Volume 764- 765)
    - Transcript of books, 1914-1915 (Oversizebox-folder 418 / 1-3)
    - Transcript of books, 1915-1916 (Oversizebox-folder 419 / 1-3)
    - Transcript of books, 1917-1918 (Oversizebox-folder 420 / 1-3)
    - Transcript of books, 1918-1920 (Oversizebox-folder 421 / 1-3)
    - Transcript of books, 1921-1923 (Oversizebox-folder 422 / 1-3)
    - Transcript of books, 1924-1929 (Box-folder 423 / 1-6)
    - U.S. corporate income tax, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 423 / 7)
  - Organizational Records
    - Stock book: Montana Hotel Association, 1889 (Volume 766)
  - Miscellany
    - Cold storage house specifications, undated (Box-folder 423 / 8)
- Montana Improvement Company, Ltd.
  - Organizational Records
    - Articles of incorporation (typescript copy), 1882 (Box-folder 423 / 9)
- Montana Lumber and Manufacturing Company
  - Financial Records
    - Ledger, 1889-1900 (Volume 769)
    - Ledger index, 1889-1900 (Box-folder 423 / 10)
- Montana Mine Exploration Company
  - Financial Records
    - Miscellaneous, 1906-1909 (Box-folder 424 / 1)
  - Legal Documents
    - Agreements; leases; etc., 1906-1911 (Box-folder 424 / 2)
  - Organizational Records
    - Certificate of incorporation; minutes; stockholder notices; etc., 1906-1909 (Box-folder 424 / 3)
- Montana Sampling Works / Sampling Department
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress copies, 1902 (Box-folder 424 / 4)
  - Financial and Production Records
    - Cash books, 1895-1896 (Volume 768- 769)
    - "Cupreous material on hand and metallurgical reports", 1903-1905 (Volume 770)
    - "Custom ore and concentrates sampled and purchased" (includes name of customer, name of mine, weight, assay value, and charges), 1896-1903 (Volume 771)
    - Journal, 1895-1898 (Volume 772)
    - Ledger, 1895-1898 (Volume 773)
    - "Mill record", 1904-1907 (Volume 774- 775)
    - "Ore record", 1905-1907 (Volume 776)
    - Ore statement, 1895 (Box-folder 424 / 5)
    - "Tonnage of first and second class ore", 1905 (Box-folder 424 / 6)
    - Voucher abstract, 1898-1901 (Volume 777)
- Montana Water, Electric Power, and Mining Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (re power station, machinery, pipeline, flume, etc.), 1890-1902 (Box-folder 424 / 7)
    - Miscellaneous (re water rights on Flint Creek), 1890-1901 (Box-folder 424 / 8)
  - Court Papers
    - Michael Norris vs. Montana Water, Electric Power, and Mining Company court decree and related papers, 1900 (Box-folder 424 / 9)
  - Financial Records
    - Account: Bi-Metallic Mining Company and Granite-BiMetallic Consolidated Mining Company, 1894-1905 (Box-folder 424 / 10)
    - Assessments, taxes, protests, 1896-1905 (Box-folder 424 / 11)
    - Audit reports, 1907-1909 (Box-folder 424 / 12)
    - Checkstubs, 1904-1905 (Box-folder 424 / 13)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contract: Granite-BiMetallic Consolidated Mining Company (includes samples of other companies' contracts), 1901 (Box-folder 424 / 14)
    - Mining and water rights claims, 1901 (Box-folder 424 / 15)
    - Petition to Daly [Deer Lodge] County Commissioners (re road), 1901 (Box-folder 424 / 16)
    - Pole line right of way, 1901 (Box-folder 424 / 17)
    - Trust deed, 1902 (Box-folder 424 / 18)
    - Water rights (transcript of Deer Lodge and Granite county records, mining code, etc.), 1890-1902, undated (Box-folder 424 / 19)
  - Organizational Records
    - Annual report, 1906 (Box-folder 424 / 20)
    - Articles of incorporation; minutes; etc., 1891-1903 (Box-folder 424 / 21)
  - Clippings
    - Re fish ladders, undated (Box-folder 424 / 22)
- Moulton Mining Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Stockholders, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 425 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Auditor's reports, 1923-1928 (Box-folder 425 / 2)
    - General ledgers, 1884-1930 (Volume 779- 780)
    - General ledger, 1884-1930 (Box-folder 425 / 3)
    - General ledger index, 1912-1930 (Box-folder 425 / 4)
    - Journals, 1884-1930 (Volume 781- 784)
    - Journal, 1910 December-1912 January (Box-folder 425 / 5)
    - Petty ledgers, 1885-1899 (Volume 785- 786)
    - Voucher registers, 1917-1928 (Volume 787- 788)
    - Miscellaneous, 1928 (Box-folder 425 / 6)
  - Legal Documents
    - Deeds (typed transcripts from county records), 1886, 1906-1907 (Box-folder 425 / 7)
  - Maps
    - Moulton Mine workings, 1925 (Box-folder 425 / 7a)
  - Organizational Records
    - Annual statement, 1918 (Box-folder 425 / 8)
    - Articles of incorporation (Utah and Montana territories), 1880, 1884 (Box-folder 425 / 9)
    - Dividends; exchange of stock; etc., 1905, 1922 (Box-folder 425 / 10)
    - Record book (includes articles of incorporation, bylaws, minutes, etc.), 1884-1908 (Box-folder 425 / 11)
    - Stock ledger, 1881-1929 (Volume 789)
    - Stock transfer journal, 1905-1930 (Box-folder 426 / 1)
    - Stockholder lists, 1913-1923 (Box-folder 426 / 2)
- Mountain City Copper Company
  - Financial Records
    - Cost sheets, 1945-1950 (Volume 790- 794)
- Mountain Consolidated Mine
  - Financial Records
    - Expense estimates (re Anaconda and Mountain Con mines), 1892-1893 (Box-folder 426 / 3)
    - General office ledger, 1895-1898 (Volume 795)
    - Ledger, 1897 (Volume 796)
    - Operations journal, 1896-1897 (Volume 797)
- Mountain Trading Company (Diamondville, Wyo.)
  - Financial Records
    - Balance sheets, 1901-1910 (Box-folder 426 / 4)
    - General ledger and index, 1901-1905 (Volume 798- 799)
    - Inventories, 1930 (Box-folder 426 / 5-6)
    - Inventory, 1931 (Box-folder 427 / 1)
    - Ledger and index: store #2, 1901-1905 (Volume 800- 801)
    - Ledger and index: store #4, 1901-1905 (Volume 802- 803)
    - Payrolls, 1912-1921 (Box-folder 427 / 2-4)
    - Transcript of books, 1900-1935 (Volume 804)
    - Transcript of books: store #1, 1911-1912 (Box-folder 427 / 5-6)
    - Transcript of books: store #1, 1913-1919 (Box-folder 428 / 1-7)
    - Transcript of books: store #1, 1920-1922 (Box-folder 429 / 1-3)
    - Transcript of books: store #2 [Oakley, Wyoming], 1911-1922 (Box-folder 429 / 4-9)
    - Transcript of books: store #4 [Glencoe, Wyoming], 1911-1922 (Box-folder 430 / 1-5)
    - U.S. corporate income tax, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 430 / 6)
- National Tunnel and Mines Company
  - Financial Records
    - Cost sheets, 1945-1947 (Volume 805- 808)
- Northern Coal Company
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1900-1901 (Box-folder 430 / 7)
    - Daybook, 1900-1901 (Box-folder 430 / 8)
    - Ledger, 1900 (Box-folder 431 / 1)
- Northern Montana Natural Gas Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Butte office: A-E, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 431 / 2)
    - Butte office: George M. Fowler, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 431 / 3)
    - Butte office: F-J, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 431 / 4)
    - Butte office: C.J. Kelley, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 431 / 5)
    - Butte office: K-L, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 431 / 6)
    - Butte office: Montana Canadian Oil Company / T.C. Witherspoon, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 431 / 7)
    - Butte office: Montana Industrial Accident Board, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 431 / 8)
    - Butte office: M-R, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 431 / 9-10)
    - Butte office: D.G. Stivers, 1919 (Box-folder 431 / 11)
    - Butte office: S-W, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 431 / 12)
    - Gold Butte and Sweetgrass offices: A-Z, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 431 / 13)
  - Financial Records
    - Bank statements: Daly Bank and Trust Company, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 431 / 14)
    - Bank statements: First International Bank, Sweetgrass, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 431 / 15)
    - Bills, invoices, etc. (document local businesses), 1917-1919 (Box-folder 431 / 16)
    - Bills of sale, receipts, etc., 1917-1918 (Box-folder 431 / 17)
    - Boiler inspections, 1918 (Box-folder 431 / 18)
    - Cash book, 1918-1919 (Volume 809)
    - Checkbooks, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 431 / 19)
    - Compensation to employees (re wages), 1918-1919 (Box-folder 432 / 1)
    - George M. Fowler statements of receipts and expenditures, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 432 / 2)
    - Insurance policies, 1918 (Box-folder 432 / 3)
    - Inventories, 1917-1920 (Box-folder 432 / 4)
    - C.H. Jennings account (re Montana Canadian Oil Company), 1917 (Box-folder 432 / 5)
    - Journal, 1918-1919 (Volume 810)
    - C.F. Kelley statements of expenditures, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 432 / 6)
    - Ledger, 1918-1919 (Volume 811)
    - John McCalman account, 1917 (Box-folder 432 / 7)
    - Payroll, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 432 / 8)
    - Taxes, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 432 / 9)
    - Trial balances, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 432 / 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 432 / 11)
  - Legal Documents
    - Agreements: Mt. Stephens Oil Company; C.P. Kelley; B.L. Chamberlain, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 432 / 12)
    - Lists of leases (includes acreage, location, rental), 1914-1917 (Box-folder 432 / 13)
  - Organizational Records
    - Stock book, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 432 / 14)
  - Reports
    - John M. Gillie report to C.F. Kelley on drilling operations in Sweet Grass Hills, 1918 October (Box-folder 432 / 15)
- Northwest Coal Company / Northwest Coal and Feed Company
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book, 1900 January-April (Box-folder 433 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Balance sheets, 1900 (Box-folder 433 / 2)
    - Cash book: Northwest Coal Company, 1898-1900 (Box-folder 433 / 3-5)
    - Cash book: Northwest Coal and Feed Company, 1899-1900 (Box-folder 433 / 6-7)
    - Cash book: Northwest Coal and Feed Company, 1900 (Box-folder 434 / 1-3)
    - Cash book: Northwest Coal and Feed Company, 1900-1902 (Volume 812)
    - General ledger, 1898-1902 (Volume 813- 814)
    - Petty ledger, 1900 (Volume 818)
    - General ledger index, 1900-1902 (Box-folder 434 / 4)
    - Inventory, 1900 (Box-folder 434 / 5)
    - Journal, 1900-1902 (Volume 815)
    - Ledgers: Northwest Coal and Feed Company, 1898-1900 (Volume 816- 817)
    - Petty ledger, 1899-1900 (Box-folder 435 / 1)
    - Sales books, 1898-1900 (Volume 819- 822)
    - Trial balance, 1900 May-June (Box-folder 435 / 2)
- Northwest Milling and Lumber Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1902 (Box-folder 435 / 3)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1899-1901 (Volume 823)
    - Ledger (includes amounts paid out re "elections", and re various operations at saw mill), 1899-1901 (Volume 824)
    - Miscellaneous (includes appraised value of stock, timber lands owned, goods sold to company by Anaconda lumber and mercantile departments, and statements of account), 1899-1911 (Box-folder 435 / 4)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contracts (re operation of saw mill by William J. Kendall), 1898-1900 (Box-folder 435 / 5)
- Northwest Publishing Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 435 / 6)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book, 1928-1929 (Volume 825)
  - Organizational Records
    - Articles of incorporation; minutes; notice of dissolution, 1928-1933 (Box-folder 435 / 7)
    - Bylaws, 1928 (Box-folder 435 / 8)
- Original Butte Mining Company
  - Court Papers
    - Colorado Smelting and Mining Company vs. Original Butte Mining Company complaint, summons, notice of attachment, 1896 (Box-folder 435 / 9)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash book and journal, 1881-1886 (Box-folder 435 / 10)
    - Ledger, 1882-1885 (Box-folder 435 / 11)
  - Organizational Records
    - Annual reports to Secretary of State, 1887-1897 (Box-folder 436 / 1)
    - Articles of incorporation, 1881 (Box-folder 436 / 2)
    - Bylaws; minutes, 1882-1897 (Box-folder 436 / 3)
    - Stock journal, 1881-1893 (Box-folder 436 / 4)
    - Stock ledger, 1881-1893 (Box-folder 436 / 5)
    - Stockholder lists, 1885-1893 (Box-folder 436 / 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1881-1897 (Box-folder 436 / 7)
- Parrot Silver and Copper Company
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book (includes ore statements), 1892 (Box-folder 436 / 8)
    - Letterpress book (includes ore statements), 1905-1911 (Box-folder 437 / 1)
  - Financial and Production Records
    - Cash books, 1881-1911 (Volume 826- 834)
    - Cost sheets (six-month reports), 1905-1909 (Volume 835)
    - Distribution book, 1902-1905 (Volume 836)
    - General ledgers, 1882-1911 (Volume 837- 842)
    - General ledger index, 1882-1884 (Box-folder 437 / 2)
    - General ledger indexes, 1882-1884, 1902-1911 (Box-folder 437 / 3-4)
    - General ledger index, 1897-1902 (Volume 840)
    - Journals, 1882-1911 (Volume 843- 846)